{"tossups": [{"question": "Its proponents cite <em>Coleman v. Miller</em> as precedent allowing a \u201cthree-state strategy\u201d for its adoption. A campaign against this legislation was led by the Eagle Forum\u2019s Phyllis Schlafly, who worried it would discriminate against housewives. Alice Paul first proposed, for ten points, what non-ratified constitutional amendment that would outlaw discrimination based on sex?", "answer": "John <b><u>Muir</u></b> (2)Leo Gorcey demanded $400 for his inclusion in this artwork. Jann Haworth and Peter Blake produced this work, which features three depictions of Shirley Temple and one of Stu Sutcliffe. Gandhi and Hitler were removed from this artwork, whose central figures wear yellow, pink, blue, and red military uniforms. Dozens of cardboard cutouts are arranged in the background of, for ten points, what artwork that was mass produced with a record that includes \u201cA Day in the Life\u201d and \u201cLucy in the Sky with Diamonds\u201d by The Beatles?  ANSWER: the album <b><u>cover</u></b> for <b><u>Sgt. Pepper</u></b>\u2019s Lonely Hearts Club Band (3)The last monarch of this country became the only European monarch to be later elected Prime Minister. Theodor Dannecker\u2019s attempt to have this country\u2019s Jewish population deported were resisted by Tsar Boris III. One dissident from this country was murdered in the Umbrella Incident. This home of Georgi Markov was ruled by communist Todor Zhivkov. Byzantine Emperor Basil II was known as the \u201cslayer\u201d of this country\u2019s people. For ten points, name this European country with capital Sofia.  ANSWER: <b><u>Bulgaria</u></b> (4)Esther Peterson opposed this legislation in favor of \u201cspecific bills for specific ills.\u201d Support for it was removed from the Republican platform in 1980. Its proponents cite <em>Coleman v. Miller</em> as precedent allowing a \u201cthree-state strategy\u201d for its adoption. A campaign against this legislation was led by the Eagle Forum\u2019s Phyllis Schlafly, who worried it would discriminate against housewives. Alice Paul first proposed, for ten points, what non-ratified constitutional amendment that would outlaw discrimination based on sex?  ANSWER: <b><u>Equal Rights Amendment</u></b> (or <b><u>ERA</u></b>) (5)As a teenager, this ruler put down a rebellion led by Jhujhar Singh. The Battle of Tilpat was a victory for this ruler, which resulted in the end of the Jat uprising led by Gokula. This ruler established a system of law known as Fatawa-e-Alamgiri. This ruler reinstated the jizya tax for non-Muslims, which had been abolished by Akbar the Great. This ruler\u2019s mother was laid to rest in the Taj Mahal. For ten points, name this Mughal emperor and son of Shah Jahan.  ANSWER: <b><u>Aurangzeb</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this leader of the Sinaloa cartel who was interviewed by Sean Penn prior to his third arrest in 2016.", "answer": "<b><u>El Chapo</u></b> or Joaquin Archivaldo <b><u>Guzm</u><u>\u00b4</u><u>an</u></b>Loera (7)Members of this ruler\u2019s court were tried for treason in the Merciless Parliament. One of this ruler\u2019s supporters, Robert de Vere, was defeated outside of Oxford by the forces of the Lords Appellant. This ruler was succeeded by the son of John of Gaunt. This son of Edward the Black Prince attempted to collect poll taxes, leading to Wat Tyler\u2019s Peasants\u2019 Revolt. For ten points, name this last Plantagenet King of England who was forced to abdicate by Henry IV, leading to the War of the Roses.  ANSWER: <b><u>Richard III</u></b> of England (8)Future governor George McDuffie led a boycott in response to this act. It was unusually proposed by Southern Democrats, who planned it to be voted down by New England Whigs opposed to its impact on wool imports. This protectionist act was expected to be repealed with the defeat of John Quincy Adams. The <em>South Carolina Exposition and Protest</em> was written by John Calhoun in opposition to, for ten points, what 1828 tariff, the highest ever in American history, which triggered the Nullification Crisis four years later?  ANSWER: Tariff of <b><u>Abominations</u></b> (accept <b><u>Tarif f of 1828</u></b> before mentioned)  (9)In 1995, seven hostages from this country were able to overpower their Taliban captors and fly home. During another hostage crisis, this country was criticized for indiscriminately flooding a theater with poison gas. On \u201cKnowledge Day\u201d in 2004, terrorists demanding independence from this country occupied a school in Beslan; nearly 200 children died in that siege in North Ossetia. For ten points, name this country, which controls Chechnya.  ANSWER: <b><u>Russia</u></b> (10)This work describes how discipline learned in a former home country was not needed in America in the section \u201cThe Dilemma of Virtue.\u201d This work was criticized for over-reliance on interviews with Robert Hashima and people kept at Manzanar and other internment camps, as its author could not travel to the subject country during wartime. Shame culture and guilt culture were compared in, for ten points, what 1946 study of Japanese culture by Ruth Benedict?  ANSWER: The <b><u>Chrysanthemum and the Sword</u></b> <b>SecondQuarter</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This event was caused by a breakdown in diplomatic relations regarding American debt owed to the pre-revolutionary government in France. The XYZ Affair was one cause of, for ten points, what officially-not-declared war that lasted from 1798 to 1800.", "answer": "Lake <b>Maracaibo</b> (2)During this conflict, in response to Quaker George Logan\u2019s attempt to create peace, Congress banned citizens from making unauthorized international diplomacy. The <em>Retaliation</em> was captured and re-captured in this conflict, which was ended by a treaty signed at Mortefontaine, which dissolved an alliance created in 1778. This event was caused by a breakdown in diplomatic relations regarding American debt owed to the pre-revolutionary government in France. The XYZ Affair was one cause of, for ten points, what officially-not-declared war that lasted from 1798 to 1800.  ANSWER: <b><u>Quasi</u></b>-War", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Lorenzo Ghiberti\u2019s bronze doors were meant to rival those on this maritime city\u2019s Baptistry.", "answer": "<b><u>Pisa</u></b> (5)A <em>Newsweek</em> cover about this conflict depicts the <em>Hermes</em> with the caption \u201cThe Empire Strikes Back.\u201d Mount Tumbledown was captured in this war, which included landings at San Carlos Water and fighting at Goose Green. Exocet missiles helped sink the <em>Sheffield</em> in this war, in which the <em>General</em> <em>Belgrano</em> was also sunk. The capture of South Georgia Island triggered, for ten points, what war in which Leopoldo Galtieri attempted to reclaim the Malvinas Islands from the United Kingdom?  ANSWER: <b><u>Falklands</u></b> War", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "That building inspired a similar house by this man\u2019s student, Philip Johnson. This creator of the glass-clad Farnsworth House succeeded Hannes Meyer as the third director of a design school that was closed in 1933 under pressure from the Nazis. For ten points, what modernist architect and final director of the Bauhaus coined the phrase \u201cless is more?\u201d", "answer": "<b><u>S</u></b>pecial <b><u>A</u></b>ir <b><u>S</u></b>ervice (6)One of this man\u2019s buildings was derided as a crypto-Communist \u201cthreat to the New America\u201d by <em>House Beautiful</em> magazine in 1953. That building inspired a similar house by this man\u2019s student, Philip Johnson. This creator of the glass-clad Farnsworth House succeeded Hannes Meyer as the third director of a design school that was closed in 1933 under pressure from the Nazis. For ten points, what modernist architect and final director of the Bauhaus coined the phrase \u201cless is more?\u201d  ANSWER: Ludwig <b><u>Mies</u></b> van der Rohe", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b><u>This leader issued the seisachtheia</u> [says-ACK-the-uh]<u>, which cancelled debts and ended</u></b> <b>slave labor as a means of paying debts. He organized the boule as a council of 400 citizens, who were eligible to serve if they produced 200 medimnoi of goods or more; that council</b> <b><u>was expanded to 500 by (+)</u>  Cleisthenes [KLICE-the-nees]. The power of the Areopagus</b> <b>was reduced by this man\u2019s reforms, which preserved (*) </b>Draco\u2019s punishments for homicide. For ten points, name this leader who reformed the Athenian constitution in the early 6th century BC.", "answer": "<b><u>Solon</u></b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man played Luis Fernandez, a POW along side Michael Caine\u2019s Captain John Colby,</u></b> <b>in 1981\u2019s </b><em><b>Victory </b></em><b>, inspired by the \u201cDeath Match\u201d played in Start Stadium in Ukraine. This athlete, who never lost a match while playing alongside Garrincha, remains the only player</b> <b><u>to win three (+)</u> </b> <b>FIFA World Cups. He was declared a \u201cnational treasure,\u201d preventing</b> <b>a transfer to Europe from Santos for 18 years before he joined the NASL\u2019s (*) </b>New York Cosmos. For ten points, name this legendary Brazilian forward, widely considered the best soccer player of the 20th century.", "answer": "<b><u>Pele</u></b> (or Edson Arantes do <b><u>Nascimento</u></b>)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "<b><u>In what is now this city, Colonel William Shy died defending a hill now named for him.</u></b> <b>Shortly after losing at Franklin, John Bell Hood\u2019s army was decisively beaten again over <u>two days in this city, ending his military career. A (+)</u>  convention held in this city brought</b> <b>southern delegates together to discuss the Compromise of 1850, but did not advocate secession. This city became the last Confederate state (*) </b>capital to secede and the first to be taken by Union forces, who arrived shortly after winning at Fort Donelson. For ten points, name this city on the Cumberland River, from which Andrew Johnson served as Military Governor of Tennessee.", "answer": "<b><u>Nashville</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This composer reused a march from his unfinished opera</u> </b><em><b><u>Undine</u> </b></em><b><u>for the Allegretto</u></b> <b>of his second symphony, which quoted three Ukrainian folk songs. He wrote a piece to benefit wounded soldiers in the Turko-Serbian war. Nikolai Rubenstein rejected his first</b> <b><u>piano concerto, which (+)</u>  Van Cliburn performed in Moscow in 1958 to win his namesake</b> <b>piano competition. This composer of the </b><em><b>Marche Slave </b></em><b>and </b><em><b>Little Russian </b></em><b>Symphony wrote another work featuring (*) </b>\u201cLa Marseillaise,\u201d \u201cGod Save The Tsar,\u201d and some cannon fire. For ten points, name this Russian composer of the <em>1812 Overture</em>.", "answer": "Pyotr Ilyich <b><u>Tchaikovsky</u></b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>This group created settlements known as \u201creductions\u201d to convert the Tupi-Guarani in</u></b> <b>Paraguay. The bull </b><em><b>Regimini militantis Ecclesiae </b></em><b>approved of this group\u2019s formation, but <u>limited it to 60 members until (+)</u>  Pope Julius III removed that limit. One member of this</b> <b>group, Jean de Br\u00b4ebeuf integrated settlers of New France with the Hurons, and members of this group who traveled to (*) </b>Asia included Matteo Ricci and St. Francis Xavier. The motto \u201cAd maiorem Dei gloriam\u201d is held by, for ten points, what Catholic counter-reformation group founded by Ignatius of Loyola?", "answer": "<b><u>Society of Jesus</u></b> or <b><u>Jesuit</u></b>s", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This party reduced working time to 35 hours per week with the Aubry laws. One</u></b> <b>winning candidate from this party won on the 110 Propositions, which involved the creation of a solidarity tax on wealth. The first cohabitation took place between that party leader</b> <b><u>and (+)</u>  Jacques Chirac from 1986-1988. Dominique Strauss-Kahn, the former head of</b> <b>the IMF, was a member of this party, whose current head has stepped up (*) </b>attacks in the Middle East in response to the Bataclan shootings. For ten points, name this French center-left party, whose leaders have included Francois Mitterand and Francois Hollande.", "answer": "<b><u>Socialist</u></b> Party of France", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b><u>This leader\u2019s regime is the subject of Mario Vargas Llosa\u2019s</u> [yoh-sa\u2019s]</b><em><b><u>The Feast of the</u></b></em> <em><b>Goat </b></em><b>. Johnny Abbes Garcia led the SIM, a secret police force under this leader. The OAS imposed sanctions on this leader\u2019s country after he ordered a failed assassination attempt on</b> <b><u>(+)</u> </b> <b>Venezuelan president Romulo Betancourt. This leader\u2019s government was responsible</b> <b>for the deaths of thousands of Haitians in the (*) </b>Parsley massacre, and he was assassinated in an ambush outside Santo Domingo in 1961. For ten points, name this dictator of the Dominican Republic.", "answer": "Rafael <b><u>Trujillo</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>During this war, the Treaty of Easton reversed some of the provisions of the Walking</u></b> <b>Purchase. In this war, James Abercrombie blundered by ordering a frontal assault with <u>no artillery support at the Battle of (+)</u>  Carillon. During this war, an army landed at</b> <b>L\u2019Anse-au-Foulon then climbed a high cliff under nightfall; in the ensuing battle, opposing generals Louis-Joseph de (*) </b>Montcalm and James Wolfe died on the Plains of Abraham, leading to the British conquest of Quebec City. For ten points, name this theater of the Seven Years\u2019 War that cemented British North American colonialism.", "answer": "<b><u>French and Indian</u></b> War [or La <b><u>Guerre de la Conquete</u></b>, <b><u>Fourth Intercolonial War</u></b>, or <b><u>Quatrieme Guerre intercoloniale</u></b>; prompt on Seven Years\u2019 War]  <b>Extra Question </b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker!", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Shortly after becoming a republic, this country\u2019s Liberal Party and Conservative</u></b> <b>Par<u>ty fought each other during the Thousand Days\u2019 War. The assassination of Jorge</u></b> <b><u>Eliecer (+)</u>  Gaitan in this country led to a 1950s civil war known as La Violencia.</b> <b><u>This countr</u>y\u2019s president, Jose Manuel Santos, is currently in negotiations with the Marxist (*)</b>guerilla group FARC to end ongoing fighting. In 1903, this country\u2019s northern  department separated to become Panama. For ten points,name this South American country  whose capital is Bogota.", "answer": "<b><u>Colombia</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}